

<u>■ Reom03@gmail.com</u>

O Lord Cochrane 302, 417, Santiago, 8331163, Chile

995145084

Details

Nationality Venezolano/a Date / Place of birth

07/10/1981 / Altagracia de Orituco

Profile

More than 10 Years experience in Technology, starting on Development (and personally the most interesting part of IT) and leading teams from a technical point of view, now I'm dedicated to manage the IT area of a Transnational company which core is an eCommerce Web Application.

Knowledge of several technologies, all open source, mainly Java y Grails/groovy, DB design, software architecture design, etc. Currently learning Machine Learning and Python.

Employment History

Cofounder, DefSystems, Santiago Chile

April 2020 — Present

Our company is in charge of the design and the development of Web applications requested by the clients, currently developing an Online Dispute Resolutions System for the Chambers of Commerce of Santiago.

We manage the entire IT Area of the APEC's B2B marketplace, called MondeB2B (-https://www.mondeb2b.com/) where I'm the Technical Leader of the Development Team.

IT Manager, Fromozz, Santiago, Chile

October 2015 — April 2019

Design and development of B2B application for integration between Retailers and Brands, developed in Grails, with DB PostgreSQL and deployed in AWS. Knowledge in: Groovy / Grails, Git, Jenkins, task management in Jira. Leading a team of 5 people, with developers, testers and AWS architects.

Proyects:

https://www.chileb2b.cl/

https://www.ecuadorb2b.com/

https://fromozz.com/

IT Consultant, VASS Latam, Santiago, Chile

August 2014 — September 2015

Maintenance and development of Web Applications in Hibu. using technologies such as Spring, Mybatis, Hiberante, Tomcat, DB: MySQL, Oracle

IT Specialist, Banco Venezolano de Credito, Caracas

Analysis, Development and maintenance of applications related to Online Banking.

Leader of the Venecredit Office Banking Project, which is the

Online banking for companies.

Experience in: Java 6, Struts 2, Spring, Jax WS, DB Informix, DB Oracle 11G, PL / SQL Hibernate 3, JPA, Jquery, Bootstrap, JavaScript, Project management.

Java Developer Jr II, Teravision Technologies, Caracas

July 2010 — July 2011

Development and maintenance of the SOMA Applications, version 1.8 and version 2.0, used for the maintenance of Aircraft, Flight Operation, etc.

Experience in: J2EE, JSP, JSTL, Spring, Hibernate, MySQL, J query, Blueprint, Jasper Report, Open Report, Tomcat, Eclipse IDE, SVN

Consultant, Y&V Consulting, Caracas

January 2010 — November 2011

Development and maintenance of WEB applications for Banco Venezolano de Credito.

Experience in:

J2EE, JSP, JSTL, STRUTS, ORACLE PL-SQL, Oracle JDBC, IText, Ajax, Axis Web Services, Jboss, Application server

Use of: Eclipse IDE, JDeveloper, CVS

Java Developer, Hidroven C.A., Caracas

June 2007 — January 2010

Analysis, Design and Programming of the Information Systems required by the company in the Java Programming language using NetBeans IDE 5.5.1 Tool, with MySQL database, with Knowledge of:

J2EE, JSP, JSTL, Struts Framework

Java Programmer, Administradora Danoral, Caracas

March 2006 — May 2007

Develop an administrative software for the management of buildings, built in Java and MySQL database.

Education

TSU at Computer Science, Rodolfo Loero Arismendi, Caracas

January 2001 — March 2004

Links

<u>Image IA Processing API</u> <u>Current Proyect</u>

Skills

| Java Programming | Grails | |
|------------------|--------|--|
| | | |
| Angular | CSS3 | |
| | | |

| RestFull API | Android App Development |
|--|--|
| Agile and Scrum | Groovy |
| Spring Framework | Oracle |
| PostgreSQL | |
| Languages | |
| Spanish | English |
| References | |
| Saul Ordoñez from Banco Venezolano de Credito | Juan Olea from MondeB2B juan.olea@mondeb2b.com (+1)904 |

Raul Ortiz Machado from Defsystems

freddy.pineda@def4u.com |-(+56)966421011

sordonez@venezolano.com |-

Courses

+584141162409

AWS Machine Learning Scholarship, Udacity

June 2020 — Present

Oracle Database 11G, Advanced PL/SQL, Oracle

March 2013 — March 2013

Angular, Udemy

June 2018 — 2018

Certifications

Sun Certified Java Programmer, Caracas

March 2005 — March 2005

Scrum Fundamentals Certified, Santiago

November 2016 — November 2016

juan.olea@mondeb2b.com | (+1)904 5894420

Sebastian Jaramillo from MondeB2B

sebastian.jaramillo@mondeb2b.com |- (+56)969072889